Lindor
they're great sweets
they the lint company have now got so
many different flavors of these Lindor
bowls but the originals are still my
favorite and they're your favorite
bold most of us are OG with Lindor balls
I've never made an ice cream with them
my original idea was to
scoop the insides out
to make it with just a ganache but
just end up eating the outside so we're
gonna make a Lindor ice cream
[Music]
welcome back to Polar Ice Creamery I'm
Nick today as I mentioned gonna make
Lindor ice cream no add-ins in this at
all it's actually I've made quite a
large mix here so you'll see a good
amount of sugars going into this but
I've filled my ice cream machine up to
its Max I will put a nominal amount of
ingredients in the description below to
make a one to one and a half liter size
base for you and then you can double it
triple it half it whatever you want to
do for napping on
so how do we make this Lindor
ice cream
let's find out
so as every recipe we make here I mean
bar one or two we're gonna start with
our milk in the pan and to that we're
gonna add in our sugars we've gone for a
little bit of sucrose and then a good
old load of dextrose why because
chocolate ice cream has a habit of going
harder than others in the freezer so you
can afford a little bit more sugars if
it's dextrose you're using and that will
give you a nicer scoop to your chocolate
ice cream once the sugars are no they're
not divided once the sugars are
dissolved and the milk has come up to a
reasonable temperature again we're not
using a thermometer here it just needs
to be warmed add in your cocoa powder
we've gone for guitars cocoa powder here
which is incredibly Good Very silky
borderline milk chocolate flavor
get that mixed in well then add in your
milk powder again make sure it's really
well dissolved you don't want any lumps
in there so make sure it's completely
Incorporated finally you can turn the
heat off and add in your Lindor balls
and just slowly mix them in until
they're completely melted and as you can
see it's quite warm at the moment
because these things are just exploding
in my fingers
once it's nicely combined and the
texture looks amazingly silky like this
you can take it off the hob and put it
in a container
as usual we add in our cream one final
Little Mix put it in the fridge for a
few hours to chill down
[Music]
after your base is completely chilled
take it out give it one final Little Mix
and then you're going to put it in your
machine as normal depending on the size
of the mix this will take anywhere from
12 to 15 minutes to churn again like I
said I've made quite a large batch here
there's no fancy add-ins so once it's
churned to your liking take it out your
ice cream machine and pop it in a
container in the freezer it goes for
three or four hours
[Music]
what are Lindor bowls they are a milk
chocolate shell filled with a very
unique as my wife gently moves my phone
out of shot with a very unique ganache
filling the ganache melts in the warmer
weather goes nice and solid not hard
solid in the cooler weather they're just
really nice texturally very nice it's a
very emotive kind of chocolate that
these things are they are bloody
expensive but worth it every time so we
decided to use the gitards cocoa powder
as it reflects in the light
this is a really really good quality
cocoa powder I mean the company guitar
has been around for donkeys years so
they know what they're doing as far as
chocolate is concerned this is no
exception so you know everyone goes on
about Varona it is it is possibly the
best cocoa powder I've found yet but
this comes in a really close second
because it creates a different kind of
chocolate ice cream it creates something
that's a bit more in line with milk
chocolate and not that super dark Punchy
fudgy dark chocolate so there's a cocoa
powder for everyone these two go really
well together let's get some scooped up
and see what the result is
[Music]
Scoops nicely it's just the right
density it just freezes just right so
that if you take it out of freezer you
can dig your spoon in and just go none
of this waiting around it's a personal
preference if you don't want a really
soft scooped ice cream or you don't want
it to be soft enough to scoop you can
reduce the sugars all these kind of
things can be done to your preference so
if you want a lower sugar ice cream you
can drop the sugars it will go harder in
the freezer and you might get a touch of
iciness to it because the way ice cream
freezes depending on the sugar content
means it all freeze faster in your
machine which is great because that will
mean a smaller Ice Crystal but you've
then gotta wait for it to defrost and
there's a whole science thing that I'm
sure I don't actually understand but hey
I make bloody good ice cream I do need
to understand it all let's see what this
ice cream tastes like shall we
I could quite easily just sit there and
eat that whole tub
that is incredible it's incredibly
smooth
has no eyes no detectable ice crystals
in there and weirdly enough for this
recipe I went a bit Rogue I didn't use
the ice cream calculator well no I lie I
did for half the recipe and then I just
ignored it after adding the actual Lindo
balls in I didn't calculate the sugar
that was in those I didn't calculate you
know the additional fats that were in
that chocolate at all so you can create
something spectacular without following
an exact scientific approach to ice
cream there are a lot of people out
there that will literally punish you
let's be fair the internet is full of
those kind of people that say you must
do this and you must do that absolutely
not it's rubbish you can do whatever you
want as long as you're happy with the
result now this is a classic case of
perfect Bloody chocolate ice cream it's
really good and I think we probably are
just gonna sit here and have a good old
bowl of this after our dinner tonight
but
if you can't get Lindor chocolate where
you are you could sub it for another
milk chocolate ice cream no you could
sub it for another milk chocolate the
result won't be the same as this because
Lindor has a very unique flavor that you
can't get anywhere else but you could
try a different lint chocolate Maybe
one of the milk chocolate varieties and
see how that works you don't also need
to use guitars you could use whatever
cocoa powder you like
you are free to make your ice cream as
you want to you don't have to follow
everyone's rules I'm here to give you an
idea of how to make all these different
flavors you can pick and choose whatever
ingredient whatever flavor whatever
element you want out of my videos and
you can just roll with it and make it
your own more than happy for you to do
that if you do that let me know how it
goes let me know if you've changed
something and how the resulting ice
cream turned out I'd love to know how
your ice cream goes some people send us
great photos on Instagram I'll put the
links here just so you can find us on
there
I I don't really do Facebook because it
just irritates me now so you probably
find less posts on there but we do keep
going on Instagram so make sure you go
and find us over there as well don't
forget to like And subscribe thanks so
much for watching and we'll see you next
time